Over the last 4 years, I've made over
10,000 static ads. And statics can and
do perform at the top of the funnel when
they're done correctly. But in the world
of AI, so many brands are still getting
their static ads strategy wrong. So
today I'm going to be sharing with you
everything that I've learned about
static ads over the last few years, and
showing you what to do and what not to
do when you make this ad type. So let's
get into it. And just to prove to you
that I at least somewhat know what I'm
talking about, uh here are some static
ads that we've made at the top of funnel
that have gone on to spend hundreds of
thousands, if not millions, of dollars
uh for the brands we work with over the
last few years. It's a common belief
that only bottom of funnel statics work
inside of ad accounts, but when you do
top of funnel statics correctly, they
can and do work, and that's what I'm
going to be showing you today.
So, we are going to split into three
parts. We're going to first cover
strategy and systems, and then we're
going to go into messaging principles,
and then design principles. All the
things you need to know to make great
static ads. So let's start with strategy
and systems. Now, let's talk about some
of the top static formats that we've
seen in our ad accounts. There's nothing
revolutionary about these, and I think a
lot of times, uh when it comes to static
ads, a lot of brands try and reinvent
the wheel. You do not have to reinvent
the wheel. There are a handful of ad
formats that work again and again and
again. And obviously, messaging is more
important than format. I'm going to go
into messaging in a moment, but don't
think about, you know, trying to be too
cute or too clever with your ad formats.
Just use the ones that are proven, and
then focus on finding the right message
for them. So,
>> [clears throat]
>> headline and benefits. Very clear
headline. The headline is the ad. You've
got the products, and then you've got
the benefits around it. Testimonials.
These are one of my favorite formats to
run, especially if you've got a lot of
reviews or a lot of ad comments, if
you're a, you know, not a a new uh
startup. Um you will have a lot of
golden nugget testimonials in here, and
you can just literally put them straight
onto on the ad on the ad. A lot of
people here try to paraphrase customers
or like move certain things around. You
don't have to do that. In fact, many
times that we have taken the exact words
or phrase that a customer has used and
put it straight into an ad. Even if it
didn't feel like quite right, or if it
didn't make sense grammatically or
whatever, it's going to work because it
is an actual customer saying that. It is
a customer talking to a customer rather
than a business talking to a customer.
So, I'm a massive fan of testimonial
ads. And obviously, offer-based ads. I
don't want you guys to get the
impression that I'm I'm just saying only
do top of funnel ads. You want all of
them. You want the top of funnel ads and
you want the bottom funnel statistics
because all of them working together uh
will hit different people who are at
different parts of the funnel. So, we
absolutely are still doing top of funnel
sorry, bottom funnel ads as well. Also
here, we have persona-based ads, which
I'm going to talk about more shortly.
Collection ads, if you have multiple
SKUs, these absolutely crush scooping up
demand at the bottom of funnel. So, I
would highly recommend doing these.
Comparison ads, whether that be a before
and afters, us versus them, kind of
timeline ads, anything where you're
comparing
a before state to an after state
and showing that ideally visually, they
are always going to be a tried and true
format. And then some slightly uglier
ones that we have here, publication ads,
press hits, native ads. All of these
formats can pretty much work regardless
of what your brand is, what you're
selling
because again, they are they are tried
and tested ad formats. And then and by
the way, I've actually I've put these in
an order in which I would prioritize
them. Like these on the first two or
three pages, I'd say the ones that we
use the most. Then you have a policy
ads, which I'm not the biggest fan of,
but they do tend to find themselves at
the top of a lot of ad accounts that I
come across. So, yeah, and they're a bit
gimmicky, but they seem to be working.
And then posted notes, also massive fan
of them and meme ads as well. I'd say
across those 12, that's probably like 95
to 98% of the statistics that we make.
You don't have to complicate things. You
don't have to go outside of, you know,
these 12 formats and and this is
definitely, you know, what the ones that
I generate in in Claude code cover for
the vast majority of time. Now, the
really cool thing that you can do is if
you go inside of Parker, which is the
tool that I have created and spoke about
on this channel before, is you can
actually go and find more ads like this
inside of the discovery tab. You can
just go and you know, if you want to go
and find some
uh posted note ads, you can come inside
of here and filter to posted note and it
is going to go and find you all of the
posted note ads. I mean, I should have
also filtered to static if I wanted to
uh load uh just um the static posted
notes as well as
instead of the video ones. Um and you
can see all the posted note ads. And the
cool thing here is that this is sorted
by impressions. So, we take the
uh impressions rank on Facebook ad
library every single day for every
single brand in the entire database. No
other tool does this to my knowledge.
And you can see basically a library of
ads that are performing for this
specific tag. So, as you can see here,
these are all ranked number one in the
brands
uh
ad library. You can see it was ranked
number one you know, on the 22nd, it's
still ranked number one today on the
24th of uh July. I can just basically
scroll through an
a library here from every brand in the
database of winning ads for whatever I
query. You can query language, you can
query industry, type of ad, uh ad
format, emotion, desire, uh awareness
level, um you know, how long it's been
running for, uh the length of the ad,
all sorts of things on here. You can
query to exactly what you want and um
and add to your swipe file, save it down
into your swipe file here. You can also
do this inside of Claude code. So,
funnily enough, as I was preparing for
this video, I wanted to rebuild my
static swipe file so I could, you know,
find any new inspiration. And I just
said, "I'm creating a YouTube video on
static ads, go through these brands and
find me some of the top ads by
impressions and prepare me a swipe file
myself."
And they went and did that inside of
Claude code. This is all done through
the Parker MCP, which I will put a link
in the top corner if you want to go and
install it. This is all done through the
Park RMP, of course, and it created me
this white file
uh of top ads. All of these are top ads
by impressions statics. And I can see
the Facebook ad library
I can see the Parker link. And then I
just said, "Can you go and save this to
my Parker swipe file?" And it went and
built me
this swipe file. So, now if you want to
see if you want access to every
uh ad that I've mentioned in this video,
every ad in this deck, just literally
I'm going to put the link in the
description, Claude code, and the Park
RMP built me the swipe file inside of
Parker. So, I literally just said, "Here
are the brands that I want to find uh
inspiration from, and um here's what
exactly what I want.
Go and build this swipe file for me."
And it went and did it. And I I barely
had to do any work. Now I have a swipe
file of of a bunch of top ads uh for all
the different formats that I care about.
And again, that's what I want you guys
to do. Take the transcript, go and put
it through, and say, "Go and go and
build this for me." Uh which I thought,
you know, that was a very very cool and
uh a use of Claude code and the Park
RMP. I want to talk about persona-based
advertising a little bit more. Uh if you
follow this channel, you'll know that
over the last few months I've been
talking a lot about the idea of making
ads that speak to one specific persona.
You know, traditional advice was to make
ads that are broadly relevant to as many
people as as possible, so you can have
the biggest addressable market. Uh and
yeah, that is still the case to an
extent, but also thinking about like in
a feed that is hyper relevant to every
single person, how can you zero in on
one person, speak to one person, and
make a whole uh funnel for that person.
And one of the best people doing this is
Alex Hormozi, who talks about it a lot.
And if you go to his ad library, you'll
see a lot of ads like this. If you're a
window installation company doing this,
if you are a real estate brokerage doing
a million a year, if you're a property
management company doing a million a
year, this is the most um
extreme version of this concept. It can
be something a little bit uh less
direct. It could be how you should like
what you show visually. If you show
someone in a a real estate brokerage,
then that's going to appeal to people
who own real estate brokerages. So, you
want to think about how you can speak
specifically to certain personas and not
worry about isolating other
uh you know, other personas in your
audience because you can also make ads
for them as well. If you look at
Grooons, they're a great example of this
in the e-commerce space. They made an ad
that I came across the other day in
their ad library saying, "We're looking
for girlies that feel puppy for no
reason." They go on to explain the exact
uh pain points that this person faces.
Now, this is not going to apply as much
to someone who uh is looking for a GLP-1
solution, which uh Grooons also has a
lot of uh messaging around, but it
speaks specifically to this girl. And
then when when she clicks through, there
is a landing page built specifically for
her. Six reasons why Grooons is uh your
gut's new bestie. So, the whole
experience from before the click to
purchase is made for that one specific
person. If you look at Grooons landing
pages, you'll see that they do a lot of
this. There's a you know, weight loss,
pre-menopause, menopause, male
fertility, gut health, girly. Like, all
of these are their own funnels that
they've created. They'll have the ads in
the front and then they'll have the
landing pages and then uh they'll take
them through to the product page. This
is something I'm seeing a lot in ad
accounts working. A lot of the bigger
brands that are doing it. Now, I'm
starting to see this uh you know, happen
more often with the the slightly smaller
brands. And I would highly recommend for
you thinking about who your personas are
and then creating experiences throughout
the whole funnel speaking directly to
that person. And if you want to see my
in-depth persona creation and analysis
process, then there's a link somewhere
on the screen right now you can go and
watch this video where I go into exactly
that. And that is a nice segue onto part
two, which is the messaging principles.
One of the biggest mistakes that I still
see brands making with their uh
headlines on their uh, static ads is
assuming that people will know or care
about your brand. These prospects on the
organic feed are scrolling through their
feed 100 miles an hour. They're looking
for every reason not to click or pay
even pay attention to your ad. If you
make headlines that assume that they
know or care about your brand, excluding
bottom of funnel ads, if you do bottom
of funnel ads, you know, they're if
they're offer based, that's fine. That's
for people who know who you are. Most
ads that you make or should be making
should assume that people do not know
who you are. It should be going to new
eyeballs who have not heard of your
brand. So, if you look at this ad from
Mood, the first thing that I see in this
ad is the big headline, "Love these."
If I don't know or care about Mood, uh,
like what what is there that is
immediately relevant to me that tells me
why I should buy or what this thing even
is. Even with the first, uh, line here,
"These are amazing. They do everything
they claim." That doesn't mean anything
to me as someone who's scrolling through
their feed looking at memes or, you
know, doing whatever you do on on
Instagram and TikTok. So, I really want
you guys to think about when you are
making headlines for static
specifically, is this relevant
immediately to someone who does not know
or care about my brand? Cuz I Well, at
least with the ad libraries I'm looking
at, there are a lot of brands who are
still making ads that assume that people
know or care about who they are.
Obviously, outside of, um, outside of
offer based ads. And when you do make
that assumption correctly, you make what
we call acquisition statics. Actual top
of funnel statics that can go and
convert someone who knows you and go and
convert someone who doesn't know you.
These are some examples. And by the way,
this is not easy to do. It's one of the
hardest things to do is to write a
headline for someone who does not know
or care and make it immediately relevant
to someone who's never heard of you
before. But this is where your research
is really going to come in handy,
looking through the ad comments,
customer reviews, post purchase surveys,
support tickets, Reddit, all that good
stuff. This is where it comes into its
own because the headline is the ad. And
as you can see here, these are not crazy
at all design-wise, they're actually
very simple. The headline is clear, it's
easy to read, and it stops you in your
scroll. And uh yeah, these are good,
solid static uh acquisition static
examples. And the thing is, you don't
have to always rely on writing the copy
yourself. Sometimes you can reverse
engineer what's working for other
brands. Now, we can't see what is
working in terms of inside their ad
accounts, cuz we can't see other brands'
ad accounts, but we can get a good proxy
via the Facebook Ad Library sort by
impressions feature. So, you can see
what's working by impressions. If it's
working by impressions, there's a pretty
good chance there's a lot of spend
behind it, and it's performing inside
their ad account. Now, we have the
Parker MCP installed on our Claude. So,
what I did inside of Claude codes, I
just said, "Look at my external brands'
top static ads by impressions. Find the
ones that make the most sense for us to
recreate, then draft copy for us to
recreate them." What I have done is on
um
Parker, and I kind of look at the web
app as like the control room now.
Uh I have just added all of my uh
brands inside of here that want to
follow. I've got my competitor brands,
I've got my influencer brands. And by
the way, if you haven't got Parker, you
can you can do this through the Ad
Library um
API and pull it into Claude. Uh I just
felt it was do some Parker's it's way
easier, and it uh tags everything
properly, um which I find very, very
valuable. Uh so, I've got a bunch of
brands that are not my competitors, but
I just like to follow them anyway.
Uh either they are you know, uh just
random brands, or they're brands that uh
share similar audiences with my uh
clients' brands.
Um so, I I I look at them, look at
what's working for them by impressions,
find uh
copy inside of our voice of customer for
our customer views, ad comments, which
is also all connected inside of Parker,
and I just go to recreate them. And
actually, I showed in the in the Claude
code video that I made the other day, if
you want to go and watch that, I'll put
the link in the corner, about this flow,
where it literally delivers me these
statics out of Slack. I had all of these
statics delivered through copying
statics from other brands and just
making them for my brand with my copy
and these are real
quotes from customers. These are real
customer reviews, these are real ad
comments and the cool thing is because
we we had the skill set up that we
talked about at the start of the video,
this
uh looks for white space inside our ad
account. So, we were not doing anything
around senior dogs. So, it found a
static to recreate. It made it about
senior dogs and it wrote the copy from
our customer reviews and that is a
really nice workflow to get statics made
that fill white space inside your ad
account or look for opportunities and go
and get these. And all of these are
one-shotted inside of Claude code with
the Hexfield MCP and the Parkfield MCP.
I really like them. So,
you could easily put something like this
in. Again, you can use the
uh Meta CLI and and Ad Library API if
you want to. I just find it way easier
to use Hexfield MCP and Parkfield MCP
together because I'm having so much fun
and like I said, if you watch that
Claude code video, you'll get a lot more
context on exactly what this looks like
um in in practice.
Um again, same same concept. All of this
is actual customer copy. Your customers
are your copywriters and so many times
over the last few years, I can't tell
you how many times we have had exact
words and phrases given to us by
customers, put in ad, whether it's a
headline for a static, whether it's a
hook for a video, whether it's just part
of the script and it goes and does
really well inside the ad account. You
can see the exact review this one came
from uh inside of this brand and here's
the prompt I entered into Claude code. I
just said, "Search my brand's customer
reviews, ad comments, look for uh the
most emotionally loaded phrases." And
then I got it to go through the same um
process.
Look at my ad account, uh look at um
what we haven't really tested and then
come up with ideas for copy that we can
go and then turn into statics. Again, if
you want more context on that, watch the
Claude code video that I did last week.
Um
cuz we went we went and then go and made
a a bunch of static through this uh
workflow, but yeah, couldn't vouch this
enough. Especially if you've got a lot
of customer reviews and ad comments, you
will for sure have some golden nuggets
like this that you can take and it's the
exact words and phrases. It feels like a
customer speaking to you on the
customer. That's what
uh kind of break through the noise in
the feed where everyone else is making
the same generic claims. That's how you
appeal to someone. That's how you stand
out um in a feed where everyone else is,
you know, saying the exact same thing.
Um one thing that I want you guys to
think about is
this kind of spectrum of clarity versus
curiosity. Uh because in the previous
video I said um that you want to be
clear over clever and and I 100% stand
by that. You want to be clear in your
ads, but I also want to make the
distinction that sometimes you want to
leave curiosity. You should need to work
out when do you want the sales happen.
As you can see here on the left-hand
side we have the traditional top of
funnel static that we've been talking
about in this video. Very clear, exactly
what it is, who it is for, and like how
it's relevant to them. On the right-hand
side, we have the curiosity uh native ad
where uh you know, the selling is done
partially in the primary text, but more
so in the advertorial page that you send
to. So, you should need to work out like
where you want the selling to be done.
Is it on the ad mainly or is it on the
Is it after the click? Uh just don't get
stuck in the middle. Again, it's a a one
thing that a lot of brands do. They they
are somewhere in between clarity and
curiosity and it results in you just
being stuck in no man's land. So, just
be conscious of that when you are uh
making your ads. And finally, I want to
talk about design principles. Now, you
can have the best messaging in the world
if it is designed in a hideous way
that's not easy for your prospects to
understand, then they're not going to
see the message that, you know, you want
them to see.
People don't read
ads from top to bottom. They scan. They
look for uh the thing that's most
appealing to them and they won't
necessarily go in the order that you
might think they are. And that's a good
thing cuz we can use this to our
advantage to uh guide them through the
process of of this static ad. So, for
example, what do you see here first?
Most people would see these two lines
here, "Faking it with my husband." And
this has been intentionally designed
like this. This is one of my favorite
statics uh that I've seen O Positive do
a very good job with their static ads.
This is a good ad library that I would
recommend swiping. They do a lot of this
stuff like psychology-based designed
where they make you uh they they kind of
guide you through the process of of
going through the static. You so so you
see this hook first, and that is the
thing that's going to grab your
attention on this image. Then you see
since which qualifies the prospect, and
then you see the products, and then you
see the social proof. So, if they you
know designed this in a way, for
example, where the the social proof is
first, you go, "I don't care about this.
I don't know what this brand is." But
they've hooked you by putting the most
attention-grabbing part in the biggest
sizing in the uh in the ad, and then you
go through and read the ad rather than
continue scrolling. So, it's very smart
design. It's something you want to think
about cuz statics have hooks to it. It's
not just videos. Statics have hooks, and
and here the hook is "Faking it with my
husband."
So, you want to think about when you're
creating statics from a design
perspective, uh you can control the
visual hierarchy with these three
levers: sizing, contrast, and white
space. And the thing that you want the
to be the most important message, that's
where the eye line should be landing
first, like we have got on this uh
example here. And in terms of actual
elements that you can control, you have
the placement and sizing of images, the
placement and sizing of headlines, what
you're actually saying in that headline,
obviously, uh the use of fonts and
colors, warps and distortions,
highlights, and arrows. So, there are a
lot of little things that might seem
insignificant, but like can play a big
part in making sure the prospect sees
what they're supposed to see first cuz
that is psychology-based design.
Just little things as well. Um here's an
example. Uh can make a big difference.
The ad on the left, nerve pain killer,
doesn't have any colors, and the text is
a little bit weird like the killer is in
front of the white light versus the ad
on the right where it's on two lines, so
it's easy to read. They've got the red
background for the word killer. Red
connotes in danger. So, that is way
easier for me to consume and understand
what is happening here than on the
left-hand side. Tiny change, but a big
difference in how the ad feels at least
in that first impression that you have
of it when you read it. And I'm just
kind of making this guys so that you can
take the transcript from this video and
put it into Claude code and say make a
visual out of this. You know, you can
create some kind of design agent that
looks at all of the points I've gone
through here and just, you know, as a
checklist and judges the outputs that
you have inside of Claude code. If you
want me to do more of a how-to in terms
of the actual Claude code system, let me
know
in the comments below and I can
obviously go and do that. One use case
isn't necessarily a design principle,
but like one,
really
practical use case I've had for AI
over the last year and a half with image
models is using it to create
intentionally unrealistic visuals.
So,
we're trying to make the invisible feel
visible here. All of these you can see,
if we go back to the slide earlier that
I was talking about, the customers being
your copywriters, how can we show what
people feel? Look at this one in the
middle here. I love this ad. It's one of
my favorite AI image ads. If you have
nerve pain in your foot, and I imagine
this has come from a customer review
that says like, you know, it feels like
I've got needles in my foot or something
like that. If you have that feeling, you
are going to stop for this static. So,
think about ways that you can make the
invisible visible. And again, you can
literally, you know, take a screenshot
of this page, put it into Claude code,
and say, "How can we make the invisible
visible for my brand?" Or what problems
are people saying in our customer
reviews,
in ad comments, etc.,
that we can actually go and make a
visuals for and then go and get to do
that. And again, I am doing all of this
through the Parker MCP. If you are
unsure how to do that, all you have to
do is go to customize and connectors and
add a connector and then add the Parker
MCP. Obviously, you need a Parker
account. If you do not have one, then
you can go and sign up for a free month
trial in the description below. And
another way that I use AI and image ads
is to create what I call atypical text
ads where you take text and put it in
unusual places that are relevant to your
prospect. So, for example, we've got
another nerve pain ad on the left here
writing on someone's foot. That just is
something that you would stop scrolling
for if you had foot pain and then you
read the headline. It's a good headline,
12 years of nerve pain gone in minutes.
Then it's got a picture of the product
here which is blurred out.
That kind of static I've seen work again
and again. Especially if you're writing
on the body for some reason, it just is
it just does get people's attention when
you write a message on someone's body.
Same thing with the one on the right, no
more fatigue, hot sweats, or weight gain
writing on someone's stomach. So, this
is another way that you can do this and
again, take a screenshot of this, give
it into Claude, and say, "How can I do
this for my brand?"
Or what other atypical text
opportunities are there? It doesn't have
to be right on the body. It can be
whatever's relevant to your
business. So, for example, we work with
a
and anti-dandruff brand. We did one
where we had a picture of the bathroom
mirror and we wrote a message in the
condensation. So, you can literally do
it anywhere. Anything that's relevant to
your
uh
your audience that they would recognize
right away, "Oh, okay, you know, this
makes sense for a shampoo brand. This
makes sense for a nerve pain brand. This
makes sense for a um
brand that helps you solve
>> [snorts]
>> hot sweats or weight gain. So, yeah,
that's another way you can use AI in
images. So,
to recap, use Claude Coden Hickfield to
scale volume. This is going to be the
actual system that you use to generate
all these ads. Test with intention. Make
sure you're looking for white space
inside your ad account, inside your
voice of customer. Uh use proven
formats. You don't need to reinvent the
wheel. Speak directly to specific
personas. Don't worry about isolating
other personas cuz you can make ads for
them as well.
Assume no one knows or cares. That is
the uh you know, static headlines 101.
If you do one thing from this video,
just make sure that your headlines
assume no one knows or cares if it is a
top of funnel static.
Reverse engineer winning copy. You don't
have to do it all on your own. You can
go and you can go and find
uh copy that's working for other brands.
Your customer, your copywriters.
Uh pick clarity or curiosity. Don't get
stuck in the middle. Consider the visual
hierarchy. Make the invisible visible.
And write messages in creative ways with
their typical text ads. And if you do
all of that, then you will look like
this. Happy dog.
If you want a team of experts to
implement this for you, uh we have uh
slots open at AdCritique right now.
We've been doing this for 4 years. We've
made 30,000 ads over the last few years.
Worked with almost 100 uh eight- and
nine-figure brands. If you're spending
at least 100k a month, we would love to
help you scale your brand. Here are some
of the results we've got on the screen
here. And uh if you've enjoyed this
video, give us a like. Give us a
comment. Give us a subscribe. All that
good stuff that you guys do. A lot more
content coming on the channel. Thanks
for watching, and I'll see you in the
next one.